哥倫比亞影業
哥倫比亞電影公司
製片：高蒙
呂克·貝松  作品
主演：布魯斯·威利斯
主演：加裡·奧爾德曼
主演：伊恩·霍爾姆
主演：米拉·喬沃維奇
主演：克里斯·塔克
主演：盧克·佩裡
【 第 五 元 素 】
音效：
艾瑞克·塞拉
服裝：
簡·保羅·高提
視覺特效：
馬克·史泰特森
聯合製片人：
伊恩·史密斯
剪輯：
塞爾非·蘭巨
美工：
丹·威爾
攝影執導：
蒂埃裡·阿伯加斯特
編劇：
呂克·貝松
羅伯特·馬克·卡門
改編：
呂克·貝松
製片人：
帕特裡·斯勒杜
導演：
呂克·貝松
(公元1914年，埃及)
來！快來
Come, come!
拜託！
阿奇，阿奇
阿奇，照明
Please!
Aziz. Aziz.
Aziz, light!
Aziz...
阿奇，照明
很好
我們繼續下去
“當三個星球暗淡無光時，黑洞像一扇門打開了...”
“惡魔鑽了進來，散播恐怖，製造混亂”
看見那條蛇沒有，比利？那個罪魁禍首
- 你一定要畫那條蛇
- 好，我畫了...
我畫了很多的蛇，那條蛇幾時要搞亂天下？
light.
Good.
We start again.
"When the three planets
are in eclipse...
the black hole,
like a door, is open.
Evil comes...
spreading terror and chaos."
See the snake, Billy?
The ultimate evil.
- Make sure you get the snake.
- Yes, I've got your snakes.
I got all the snakes.
When is the snake act
supposed to occur?
如果這是“五”，這是“一”
每隔五千年大亂一次
那麼，我還有點時間
你拿水去給他們喝
好孩子，還是我去吧，願神同在，遠離邪惡
這是不同的民族或是人民的象徵
聚集了四種生命元素
水、火、土、空氣，圍繞第五種
就是第五種...
元素
主啊！饒恕我，他們知道太多了
神父，你好嗎？
很好，來喝點水
If this is the five...
and this is the one...
every 5,000 years.
So, I've got some time then.
You bring them water.
Good boy.
I'll take it to them.
Go with God.
Be safe from evil.
You see here these different peoples,
or symbols of people...
gathering the four elements
of life...
water, fire, earth, air...
around a fifth one.
A fifth...
element.
Forgive me, Lord.
They already know
too much.
Father.
How are you?
- Well. You have some glasses?
- Of course.
好啊！
見到你好高興，這可是大發現
I'm so glad to see you.
It's the most extraordinary thing.
空前的大發現
It's the greatest find
in history.
對，你一定很渴
是，是，對不起
這像是打仗布陣，這邊是善，這邊是惡
這裡有武器對抗惡魔
我要出名了
祝你揚名天下，我敬你
為名氣乾杯
乾杯
乾杯不能用水
比利，拿我袋子裡的酒來
這一段我看不懂
有可能是...史前時代的事，真搞不懂...
不過，等一下，這裡...
你們看！
他們來了
這個人，這個完美的種類...
我知道這是關鍵
象形文提到“神光”，什麼是“神光”？
阿奇，照明
清楚多了，謝謝
主啊！
神父，這真不可思議，你是不是說...
你...你是德國人？
You must be parched.
Oh, yes, yes.
I'm sorry.
It's like a battle plan.
Here the good.
Here the evil.
And here, a weapon...
against evil.
I'm going
to be famous.
Then let us toast
to your fame.
To fame.
Salute.
You can't toast
with water.
Billy, in my sack,
the grappa.
This I don't understand.
This could be something...
prehistoric.
I don't know.
But, wait.
Here.
Look, look.
They're here.
This man...
this perfect being.
I know this is the key.
I know it.
This divine light
they talk about.
What is divine light?
Aziz, light!
Much better.
Thank you.
My Lord.
Father, this is the most
unbelievable thing I've ever seen.
Don't you think?
Are you German?
Lord...
主啊！他幾乎發現一切
I know he was about
to discover everything.
But, no worry.
但是不要緊，我及時阻止他了
I was there in time.
Priest...
教士，你和以前的人...
很忠心的服侍我們
you and those before you...
have served us well.
但是戰爭要來了，連地上的石頭也要遭殃
這玩意...真的很神奇
那就是第五元素
But war is coming.
Stones not safe
on Earth anymore.
This...
is really amazing.
The fifth element.
Take the stones.
My Lord...
主啊！你拿走武器，萬一魔鬼再來...
if you take the weapon,
we'll be defenseless...
when evil returns.
我們就無力抵抗
三百年後，魔鬼再來的時候
我們也會再來
教授
不要動！
In 300 years...
when evil returns...
so shall we.
Oh, Professor.
Professor.
Don't move!
I have a gun!
- 比利！
- 我有槍
請了解，他們是朋友啊！
Please, understand.
They're our friends.
Friends?
朋友？神父...
他們殺了教授，他們是怪物
我都可以解釋，比利
- 你跟他們一夥
- 比利
Father, they've killed the Professor!
They're monsters!
I'll explain everything.
- You're with them?
- Look at me.
你看我，我是你的朋友
- 不要，神父
- 比利，你看著我
I am your friend.
- No, Father.
- Billy, look at me!
Please, put...
把槍放下來
the gun down.
不要
比利，不要！
Billy, no!
Hurry!
快點，墻壁要關上了
這是你的使命,把你的知識傳給下一個教士
我願順服你，但是請快點
The wall is closing!
Here is your mission:
Pass your knowledge
to the next priest...
as it was passed to you.
I will do as
you command, but...
hurry, you still
have time.
你還有時間
時間並不重要，只有生命才重要
我會完成使命，你放心
我會傳這知識等你回來
(三百年之後)
Time not important.
Only life...
important.
I will fulfill
my mission!
You can count on me!
I will pass the knowledge
until your return.
Anything yet?
- 有沒有動靜？
- 沒有
連溫度都沒變嗎？
- Not even a temperature?
- The analyzers have jammed.
溫度計故障，一個顯示超過沸點，一個突破冰點
我們來看看
它正在成形
派出探測艇
One shows a million degrees,
the others minus 5,000.
Let's see it.
It's taking shape.
Send out a probe.
Ladies and gentlemen...
各位先生女士
（紐約市總部）
聯邦地區總統
三十秒後，和史將軍空中對話
神父，我幫你占了位子
the President of
the Federated Territories.
On air with General Staedert
in 30 seconds.
I saved this seat
for you, Father.
President on the line.
總統在線上
We're in position.
我們就定位了
我要向最高議會報告事實
分子分析還沒有結果
I have to address the Supreme Council.
Just the facts.
There are no results from the chemical
and molecular analysis yet.
All the calibers are overshot.
偵測核子來定形
這麼說，你還不知道它是什麼東西
只知道它越長越大
We're initiating
thermonucleatic imaging.
What you're saying is,
you don't know what this is.
All we know is,
it just keeps getting bigger.
Recommendation?
有什麼建議？
我的作風是，先開火後問話，我不喜歡不速之客
My philosophy is
shoot first and ask questions later.
I don't like uninvited guests.
All right, then.
就這麼辦
總統先生
Mr. President?
什麼事？
柯維多神父，天文學家
Priest Vito Cornelius,
expert of astrophenomenon.
I...
本人...有不同的理論謹呈
給你二十秒
想想看...
這東西之所以無法分析，是因為它不願被分析
have a different theory
to offer you, sir.
You have 20 seconds.
Imagine that this...
thing is not anything
that can be identified...
because it prefers not to be.
Wherever there is life...
哪有生命，它就帶死亡去
it brings death...
because it's evil.
因為它邪惡，絕對邪惡
Absolute evil.
One more reason
to shoot first.
更有開火的理由了
因為邪惡會茲生邪惡，開火只會使它更強大
探測艇五秒內抵達
Evil begets evil, Mr. President.
Shooting will only
make it stronger.
Probe will obtain objective
in five seconds.
Growth rate is at 27%.
增長率是27%
很有道理，但是沒時間分析了
時間不重要，人命才重要
你說得對，我要保護兩千億公民
Your theory is interesting,
but we don't have time to go into it.
Time is of no importance.
Only life is important.
You're right.
That's exactly what we'll do.
We'll protect the life of 200 billion
of my fellow citizens.
You may fire when ready.
準備好就開火
裝120ZR飛彈，鎖定目標
（目標熱度0%）
Up-front loading of a 120-ZR missile.
Marker lights on the objective.
（表面活動零）
表面結構轉為堅固
它預期到攻擊，這表示它有智力
Its structure solidified
on the surface.
I think it's anticipating the attack.
That denotes intelligence.
The most...
可以想像，這智力好可怕
飛彈安裝完畢
terrible intelligence imaginable.
120's loaded.
（武器啟動）
The ship is
in combat formation.
進入戰鬥位置，飛彈安裝完畢
Missiles are loaded.
- Staedert.
- Yes, sir.
- 史泰德
- 是的，長官
I have a doubt.
- 我有個疑問
- 我沒有疑問
I don't, Mr. President.
史泰德
怎麼回事？快回答
What happened?
Can you hear me?
怎麼回事？摧毀目標了沒？
正要摧毀
該星球直徑暴長200%
向太空船逼近
有沒有比240型更大的飛彈？
- Did you destroy it?
- I'm about to.
The planet has increased
diameter by 200%.
It's moving toward the ship.
What do we have
that's bigger than 240?
Nothing, sir.
沒有，將軍
史泰德，聽到沒？快點撤退
我不想出事，聽到沒？
撤退，聽到沒？
Staedert, do you hear me?
Get out of there.
I don't want an incident.
Do you hear me?
Get out of there.
Can you hear me, Staedert?
Do you understand?
Listen.
了解嗎？
注意，我是總統，我命令你
That's an order.
Do you understand me?
Do you hear me?
你明白嗎？聽到沒？撤退
天啊！
（紐約，布魯克林南區）
（公元2263年3月 清晨2點）
一天抽四根煙
Get out of there!
Good God!
Four a day.
（閒人勿近）
I'm tryin'.
我盡量
戒煙是我的目標
我醒了
To quit is my goal.
I'm up.
天啊！
All right, I'm up.
好了，我醒了
天啊
God.
Hey, dog brain,
Finger here.
我是“手指”
Hi, sweetie.
I love you too.
小寶貝
我也愛你，少校，最近沒有叫我寶貝了
You haven't called me that
since basic training.
I was talking
to the cat.
我在叫貓兒
I forgot...
你愛貓勝過愛女人
you prefer your cat
to the real thing.
At least the cat
comes back.
貓至少還會回家
Still pining
for that two-timing slut?
你還在恨那淫婦？天下有幾百萬女人
There's millions
out there.
I don't want
a million.
我不要幾百萬，我只要一個
I just want one.
The perfect one.
一個完美的女人
It don't exist, Major.
沒有這種女人
我知道沒有
Yeah, I know.
What?
Picture of you.
怎麼了？
你的相片
- How do I look?
- Like shit.
- 好看嗎？
- 死相
Must be an old picture.
那是舊相片，你得送計程車來大檢
Bring me your hack
for a six-month overhaul.
- Negative.
- A.S.A.P.
- 免了
- 越快越好
我不需要
我跟你出過上千次任務，知道你愛飆車
我現在開計程車，不是戰鬥機
你的駕照還剩幾點可以扣？
I don't need one.
Who sat next to you for 1,000 missions?
I know how you drive.
Finger, I drive
a cab now...
not a space fighter.
Tell me. How many points
you got left on your license?
Major, how many points?
少校，還剩幾點？
At least 50.
至少五十點
說謊也要打草稿，晚上見
Know what?
You gotta learn to lie better.
See you tonight.
Welcome to Paradise.
歡迎光臨“天堂樂園”
Welcome to Fhloston Paradise.
光臨“失樂園”
我是魯比，五點有現場轉播超級美夢雙子星大賽
優勝者陪我去失樂園玩兩天，鎖定“無線太空電台”
別整天看電視，看久了會變白痴
使世界完美
It's Ruby Rhod,
and I'll tell you live at five...
the winner of the super green
Gemini Croquette Contest!
The winner will go with me
for two days to Fhloston Paradise.
Tune in to Radio Cosmos.
Don't watch all day.
It'll rot your brain.
For a perfect world.
- Give me the cash.
- Been here long?
給我鈔票
站很久了嗎？
Long enough.
Give me the cash.
夠久了，給我鈔票
Is that a Z-140?
這槍是Z140型嗎？
由鈦金屬製成，由念力控制的槍型
Alleviated titanium.
Neurocharged assault model.
Good thing for me
it's not loaded.
幸好沒有上膛
沒有上膛？
It's not loaded?
You have to...
你必須...先按黃色鈕上膛
你慢慢搞吧！
要我幫你？
上膛了
給我鈔票
push that yellow button
to load it.
Take your time.
Want me to--
There you go.
Give me the cash!
That's a very
dangerous gun.
這把槍很危險，還是我幫你保管的好
Maybe you better let me
hang on to this one for you.
You don't mind, do you?
You sure?
- 你不介意吧？
- 不會
- 你確定？
- 不會，拿去
我不要了
No. Take it.
I don't need it.
That's a nice hat.
帽子很好看
You like it?
你喜歡？天啊
God!
Please enter your license.
請輸入駕照
好，等一下
歡迎，達先生
Yes, just a minute.
Welcome, Mr. Dallas.
Good morning.
- 早安
- 好睡嗎？
Sleep well? Me too.
我還好，又做惡夢了
前進，2X4
你的駕照只剩五點
謝謝你提醒我
祝你愉快
絕對愉快
I had a horrible nightmare.
Propulsion 2-X-4.
You have five points left
on your license.
Yeah, thank you
for reminding me.
Have a nice day.
Why not?
You have 48 hours.
還有48小時
正好夠它調整到適應我們
That's the time it needs to adapt
itself to our living conditions.
- And then?
- Then it will be too late.
- 然後呢？
- 從此，橫行無阻
這東西不要錢，也不要權
The goal of this thing is not
to fight over money or power...
but to exterminate life.
只要終結生命，終結所有的生態
你是說，它勢不可擋嗎？
只有一物能克它
蒙度沙瓦人有降魔的武器
四種元素，圍繞第五種元素
創造出至尊種類終極戰士來保衛生命
這五種元素產生“創造之光”，能把生命帶到宇宙的邊陲
All forms of life.
You're telling me
there's nothing that can stop this.
There is only one thing.
The Mondoshawan have in their
possession the weapon to defeat evil.
Four elements...
gathered around a fifth...
supreme being,
the ultimate warrior...
created to protect life.
Together they produce
"The Light of Creation."
Able to bring life to the farthest
reaches of the universe.
But, if...
但是...假如...
惡魔站在這裡
evil stands there...
Then what?
那會怎樣？
Then light turns to dark.
光明變黑暗
Life to death...
生變死，萬劫不復
蒙度沙瓦的太空船要求入境
准予入境，並且表示熱忱歡迎
forever.
A Mondoshawan spaceship requests
permission to enter our territory.
Give it permission to enter
with our warmest regards.
Thank you.
謝謝你
入境要求獲準
該我上場了
我們完了
阿克諾，跟地球聯絡上了
Permission to enter granted.
Show time.
We are lost.
Aknot, we are connected to Earth.
Mr. Zorg's office.
- 卓格先生辦公室
- 我是阿克諾
聽到你的聲音很高興
任務完成了
再過幾小時，你就能如願了
好，到工廠來見我
It's Aknot.
I'm so glad
to hear you, Aknot.
The mission is accomplished.
You'll have what you asked for
in a few hours.
Good.
I'll meet you at my factory.
The attack was by
two unregistered warships.
來攻的戰船都是無照的
封鎖邊界，全面警報
聯絡蒙度沙瓦人，解釋清楚
苦等了三百年，白費功夫
Close all borders and
declare a state of general alert.
Try to contact the Mondoshawans.
We owe them an explanation.
Three hundred years
of waiting for nothing.
Go get some rest.
- 去休息一下
- 不要
No.
The Mondoshawan...
蒙度沙瓦的聯絡人，就是我，他們會來找我
這是政府的事，我會通知你
- 救援組在現場報告
- 有活口嗎？
只有一個
（紐約市，核研所）
- 這也算活口？
- 我只需要一點活細胞
I am their contact.
They will come for me.
This is government business.
I'll keep you informed.
The rescue team has reported
from the crash site.
Any survivors?
Only one.
You call that a survivor?
A few cells still alive.
More than I need.
Have you identified it?
- 驗出是什麼了嗎？
- 我們盡力了
正常人有40組記憶DNA，足夠物種生生不息
這東西有20萬組
The computer went
off the charts.
Normal human beings
have 40 DNA memo groups...
which is enough
for any species to perpetuate.
This has 200,000 memo groups.
Sounds like
a freak of nature.
- 可說是異類了
- 對，我等不及想見他
Yeah, can't wait
to meet him.
You okay?
Over here.
- 要緊嗎？
- 這邊
對不起
將軍，我給你看樣東西
這是常人的DNA鏈，你、我，任何人都是
看這個
它的DNA成分跟我們的一樣，但是卻有無限的基因鏈
像是人工造出來的
Excuse me.
General, I want
to show you something.
This is a normal
human DNA chain.
You, me, anybody, right?
Watch this.
The compositional elements
of his DNA chain are like ours.
There's simply more of them,
with infinite genetic knowledge.
Almost like this being
was engineered.
Is there any danger?
- 有沒有危險？
- 沒有，沒有
We put it through
the cellular hygiene detector.
我們檢疫過了，那細胞真是...完美無瑕
The cell is,
for lack of a better word...
perfect.
Go ahead.
進行吧！
Mr. Perfect better be polite.
它最好懂禮貌，否則我拿它喂貓
進行重建
生肌長肉
（情況正常）
十秒後完成紫外線保護層
Otherwise, I turn him
into cat food.
Activate it.
Tissue processing.
Ten seconds to
ultraviolet protection.
This is the last phase.
這是最後階段，細胞被原子轟炸，迫使軀體反應，就會長皮膚
真是奇妙
重建完畢
打開罩子
我說過，完美無瑕
系上熱能帶
The cells are bombarded by atoms
which forces the body to react.
That means
growing skin.
Wonderful.
Reconstruction complete.
Remove the shield.
I told you.
Perfect.
Thermal bandages.
I'd...
我想...拍幾張照片...
記錄存檔
她說什麼？
不知道，進行語言解碼
like to take
a few pictures...
for the archives.
- What's she saying?
- I don't know.
Activate the phonic detector.
Is that thing solid?
- 那東西堅固嗎？
- 堅不可破
很好
- Unbreakable.
- Good.
If you want out...
你若想出來，得先學會溝通技巧
全面警戒
完美無瑕
（警察）
you'll have to develop
those communication skills.
General alert.
Perfect.
Ladder on 18.
降十八樓的梯子
兩個跟我走，其他人進通風管
往這邊
小姐，別衝動，我們是警察
Two men with me.
The rest in the main ventilation.
This way.
Lady, stay calm.
This is the police.
There's nowhere
else to go.
你無處可逃了，還是轉身，趴在地上
你聽得懂嗎？
她聽不懂
要飛行組支援
Slowly turn around
and put your hands on the floor.
Do you understand?
She doesn't.
I think we need
a flying unit.
This is the police.
我們是警察...
We are processing
your identification.
要檢查證件，舉雙手聽從指示
（搜尋）
（無檔案）
她沒有檔案
她跳樓了
Put your arms up
and follow our instructions.
She has no file.
She dove off.
You just had an accident.
- 你剛才肇事
- 我知道，不用你雞婆
Yes, I know I just had an accident,
you daffy bastard!
You have one point left
on your license.
你的駕照只剩一點，當心！
左轉！
Look out!
Left!
（自動化）
想不到這麼倒霉
有人生還嗎？
嗨！
你要緊嗎？
砰！我聽得懂“砰”
好大聲，好大聲，霹靂啪啦砰
I can't believe it.
Shit.
Any survivors?
Hi.
Are you okay?
Boom.
Boom. Yeah,
I understand "boom."
Bada boom.
Big.
Big bada boom.
Big...
大聲砰，啪啦砰
bada big boom.
Big boom.
- 大聲砰
- 對，大聲砰
Yeah, big bada boom.
Bada boom.
- 啪啦砰
- 大聲砰，霹靂啪啦砰
你沒死算命大
現在由警方掌控
雙手放在方向盤上
你的乘客來路不明，我們要逮捕她
Big boom.
Big bada boom.
You're lucky you're not dead.
This is a police control.
Please keep your hands
on the wheel.
You have an unauthorized passenger
in your vehicle.
We are going
to arrest her.
Thank you for cooperating.
謝謝你的合作
Sorry, honey.
抱歉，親愛的，你得搭警車了
開門
照他們的話做
抱歉
Looks like
this is your ride.
Open the door.
Do what they say.
Sorry.
（請幫助孤兒）
"Please...
求你...救我
help."
I only have one point
left on my license.
我只剩一點
現在要回廠做半年一次的大檢，懂嗎？
請你打開乘客門
求求你...
救我
我不能
I need it to get back to the garage
and get the cab a six-month overhaul.
You understand?
Can you please
open the passenger door?
Please...
help.
I can't.
I repeat...
再說一次，打開車門
open the passenger door.
Yeah, yeah, sure.
是，好的，開就開嘛
謝謝合作
救救我
手指會殺掉我
（自動化）
Why not?
Thank you
for your cooperation.
Help.
Finger's going
to kill me.
Emergency!
警急！警急！
One point has
been removed.
- 最後一點扣除
- 我知道
我真是蠢
支援追捕計程車
Yes, I know!
This is so stupid.
Assist in pursuit
of yellow cab.
Unit 47,
we're on the way...
47組，我們在路上，午餐後支援
- 兩客黃金特餐
- 謝謝
我老了、累了，還要餓肚子追飆車族
真是多謝了
after we finish lunch.
Two golden menus.
I'm too old, too tired and too hungry
to go chasing some hot rod.
Thank you so much.
And I'm definitely
too thirsty.
我渴死了
小心！
也許我們運氣好，跑一英里沒人追就安了
Look out!
We got lucky.
If they don't chase you after a mile,
they don't chase you.
Maybe two miles.
也許要兩英里
坐穩了
小姐，我只會說英語，而且是破英語
查司機的身份
Hang on.
Look, lady...
I only speak English
and bad English!
Run an ID.
（掃描車輛）
我雖然愛聊天，但是請暫時閉嘴
I'm all for conversation, but maybe
you can just shut up for a minute!
He's got a scan blocker.
- 他有反掃描裝置
- 那麼他是車賊，轟掉他
（攻擊警告）
你闖了什麼禍？
（鎖定）
Means he's a car thief.
Blast him.
I don't know
what you did...
but they are pissed off!
他們火大了
坐穩！
暫時平安了
（攻擊警告）
你們吃硬不吃軟，來狠的
老子陪你們玩
一進霧區就安了
希望到得了
這麼大的霧怎麼搜？
我們在這裡避避鋒頭
慘了！
你要緊嗎？
Hold on!
We're safe for a while.
You want to play soft?
I'll play soft.
You want to play hard?
Let's play hard.
If we get to the fog,
we'll be okay.
If we make the fog.
How do they expect us
to find anything in this shit?
We're just going to wait here until
things quiet down if you don't mind.
Shit.
You okay?
Priest.
教士
You don't need a priest,
just a doctor.
你要看醫生，不是教士
- 柯維多
- 什麼？
教士
Vito Cornelius.
What?
Priest.
Yes?
有事嗎？
- 我要找一位教士
- 禮堂在樓下一樓，恭喜
I'm looking
for a priest.
The weddings are downstairs, my son.
Congratulations.
She's not my bride.
She's my fare.
她不是要嫁我，是要找柯維多
She's looking for
Vito Cornelius.
The phone book
said he lived here.
電話簿有記載他住這裡
正是我，但是我不認識她
沒人認識她，身份不明，她手臂上有刺青
刺青？
天啊
第...
Yes, that's me,
but I don't know who she is.
Nobody does.
No file, no ID, nothing.
She's got a tattoo
on this arm.
Tattoo?
Fifth...
第五元素
element.
Finger's going
to kill me.
手指會殺了我
- Hey! Wake up!
- Who are you?
- 醒醒！
- 你是誰？
我帶那女子來的，記得嗎？
I brought the girl, remember?
The redhead.
She just dropped in on me.
她從天上掉下，講些怪語言
不是怪語言，是神國語言
Started speaking
a bizarre language.
It's not bizarre.
It's the divine language.
It's the ancient language...
是古時候通行宇宙的語言
spoken throughout the universe
before time was time.
他...
“他”是女的
He's a she.
You noticed that.
你注意到了
是的
Yes.
- It's a miracle.
- Miracle she's not dead.
- 真是奇跡
- 她居然沒死
Not a moment to lose.
Wake her up.
叫醒她，但是要溫柔，因為這女子是人類的至寶
她完美無瑕
完美無瑕
我要穿聖袍
But gently,
because this woman is...
mankind's most precious possession.
She is perfect.
Perfect.
More dignified.
Hey, lady...
小姐，醒醒
wake up.
I shouldn't
have done that.
是我不應該
你做得對
我以為你記得坐過我的車
It was wrong
to kiss you.
He said
to wake you gently.
You're right.
Just thought you might
remember me from the cab.
Remember?
記得嗎？啪啦砰
"Bada boom?"
"Big bada boom?"
霹靂啪啦砰
在車上霹靂啪啦砰，你看
我開計程車，這就是我
達·柯本
Boom. Big bada boom.
In the cab. Look.
I drive a cab.
This is me.
Korben Dallas.
Korben.
You understand?
柯本，懂不懂？
Here.
看這個，拿去
等學會英語再打電話給我
開玩笑的
你叫什麼名字？
Take it.
You can call me
when you learn English.
Just kidding.
What is your name?
You.
名字？
我叫柯本
麗露米乃裡卡芭拉蜜奈柴，伊巴克柏狄西柏
很好，你的名字那麼長？
你有沒有...短一點的名字？
短的
達·柯本
麗露
Korben.
Leeloo Minai Lekarariba-Laminai-Tchai
Ekbat De Sebat.
Good.
All that's your name?
Do you have...
a shorter name?
Short.
Korben Dallas.
Leeloo.
Korben, Leeloo.
柯本，麗露，麗露，柯本
Leeloo, Korben.
You're sure
she's a Supreme Being?
- 你確定她是神人
- 肯定是
你們是老朋友
Absolutely sure.
Old friends.
Yeah, you're right.
對，你做得對，請她還我的槍
- 你叫什麼？
- 達·柯本
- Ask her for my gun back.
- What's your name?
Korben Dallas.
Thank you for your help.
謝謝你相助，真好，但是她需要休息
You've been kind,
but now the girl needs to rest.
She's been on
a long trip.
- 她長途跋涉
- 我知道，她降臨我在場
I know.
I was there when she landed.
Wait, wait, Father.
等一下，神父
她說了一些我聽不懂的話
She said something
I didn't understand.
What does
"ekto gamat" mean?
- “伊克多格麥”？
- “我沒同意，別亂來”
我猜也是
我不該吻她
抱歉，我忘了買貓食
"Never without my permission."
That's what I thought.
I shouldn't have
kissed her.
Oh, no. I'm so sorry.
I forgot your food.
How about some
nice Thai food?
來點泰國菜，好嗎？來了，別急
幹嘛？
Yeah, yeah, hold on.
Buddy, I'm waiting
all day here.
夥計，我等了你一整天
- Finger.
- Where's the cab?
- 手指
- 車子呢？
Car's running fine.
車子跑得很好
Fine. What "fine"?
“很好”是什麼意思？
你的字典沒有“很好”，老實跟老朋友說吧！
I know you.
"Fine" ain't in your vocabulary.
You can tell your old buddy Finger
what happened.
What? You save the planet?
你是救了地球...
還是又闖禍了，對嗎？
我去你那裡的途中，天降乘客
無法拒絕的大貴客
有多大？
You dinged the fender again.
That's it, right?
I was on my way to see you,
and a fare fell in my lap.
One of these big fares
you can't resist.
How big?
Five-nine...
身高五英尺九寸，藍眼、長腿、細皮嫩肉
blue eyes...
long legs, great skin.
You know?
Perfect.
知道嗎？完美無瑕
I see.
原來如此，這個完美的乘客有名字嗎？
麗露
- 她在做什麼？
- 溫習她錯過的五千年曆史
她沉睡了好一陣
（武藝）
我知道進度落後，但是沒時間了
沒錯
And this perfect fare,
she got a name?
Leeloo.
What's she doing?
Learning our history,
the last 5,000 years that she missed.
She's been asleep
for a while.
I know she's been through a lot,
but we don't have much time.
You're right.
Chicken.
雞肉，好吃
雞肉
打擾你真抱歉，不過...
Good.
Chicken.
I'm really sorry
to interrupt you, but...
the case...
那個箱子，裝石頭的
在哪？
被偷了
誰會做這種事呢？
對不起，議會擔心經濟蕭條可能裁掉五十萬人嗎？
我猜會從車行等小公司開刀
with the stones...
where is it?
Stolen?
Who in God's name
would do such a thing?
Excuse me, sir.
The council is worried
about the economy heating up.
Is it possible
to fire 500,000?
I thought from a smaller company,
like one of the cab companies.
Fire one million.
裁掉將近一百萬人
可是五十萬...
But 500,000--
One million.
一百萬，遵命，長官，恕我打擾
這是給神人...
Fine, sir.
Sorry to have
disturbed you.
It's for the Supreme...
Sorry.
對不起
我不知道你的尺寸，還有自動眼線機
只要戴上就好了
對，有個跛腳漢
四個月前來打聽那些石頭，自稱是藝術品商
叫什麼來的？
記名字我最差了
- 他們把她造得...
- 完美無瑕
她說什麼？
她說知道石頭的下落
阿克諾，你借的兩架飛機呢？
I didn't know your size,
and I found you this makeup box.
You just put it like that.
Yes, there was
a man with a limp...
came here a month ago
asking about the stones.
Said he was an art dealer.
What was his name?
I'm bad with names.
- They really make her--
- Perfect, I know.
What'd she say?
She says she knows
exactly where they are.
My dear Aknot, how about
those two planes you borrowed?
Aknot, is that you?
阿克諾，是你嗎？這張臉好醜
不適合你
變回來
What an ugly face.
It doesn't suit you.
Take it off.
That's better.
好看多了，不要以長相為恥
Never be ashamed
of who you are.
You're warriors.
Be proud.
你是戰士，要引以為榮
如果聯邦政府要放逐你，殺不死你，你會更堅強
你復仇的時候到了
ZF1型槍
輕便，槍把可調整
攜帶方便，可分解成四部，X光偵測不到
So what if the federal government
scattered you to the wind.
What doesn't kill you
makes you stronger.
Your time for revenge
is at hand.
The ZF-1.
It's light. The handle's adjustable
for easy carrying.
Breaks down into four parts,
undetectable by X-ray. Discreet.
A word on fire power:
我來介紹火力
鈦型槍，可裝三千發，一次可發三至三百發
鎖定更方便，卓格的發明
鎖定一發
其他發都會射向同一處
卓格的發明越老越值錢
火箭發射器
Titanium recharger, 3,000-round clip,
with bursts of 3 to 300.
With the replay button,
a Zorg invention, it's even easier.
One shot...
and replay sends every following shot
to the same location.
And to finish the job,
all the Zorg oldies but goldies.
Rocket launcher.
Arrow launcher...
弓箭發射器
箭頭裝有彈頭
with exploding
or poisonous heads.
Very practical.
非常實用
拋網器
噴火器
Net launcher.
The flamethrower.
My favorite.
我的最愛
And for the grand finale...
最厲害的殺招，新急凍系統
the new Ice Cube System.
Four full crates...
四箱軍火，準時交貨
delivered right on time.
And what about you,
dear Aknot?
阿克諾，你呢？我要的帶來了嗎？
帶來了
真可觀
你聽著...
這箱子是空的
Did you bring
what I asked?
Yes.
Magnificent.
This--
This case is empty.
Empty?
空的？
空的，就是滿的相反
這箱子應該是滿的
誰要解釋？
守護者把石頭交給可靠的人了
此人改走別的路
她應該跟這人...約在飯店碰頭
Empty...
the opposite of full.
This case
is supposed to be full!
Anyone care to explain?
The Guardians gave the stones
to someone they could trust.
Who took another route.
She's supposed
to contact this person...
in a hotel.
And she's looking
for the address.
她在找那個地址，找石頭，簡單
Easy.
（天使星群）
在這裡
天使星群的失樂園星球
Dot.
It's Planet Fhloston,
in the Angel Constellation.
We're saved.
我們得救了
I'm screwed.
我完了
- 你要一箱，我們送到
- 我要箱裡的四塊石頭
不是一、二、三，是四，四塊石頭
我要空箱子幹什麼？
- 我們是戰士，不是商人
- 你會算術，看我的手指
You asked for a case.
We brought one.
A case with four stones
in it!
Not one or two or three,
but four!
Four stones!
But what the hell am I supposed to do
with an empty case?
We are warriors,
not merchants.
But you can still count!
Look at my fingers.
Four stones, four crates.
四塊石頭，換四箱軍火，沒有石頭，就沒有軍火
東西統統打包
我們冒死送來，相信會給我們一些補償
你畢竟還是商人
那就留一箱軍火給他
Zero stones, zero crates!
Pack everything up!
We're out of here!
We risked our lives.
I believe a little compensation
is in order.
So you are merchants
after all.
Leave him one crate
for the cause.
I don't like warriors.
我不喜歡戰士，死腦筋，專打沒指望的仗
Narrow-minded,
no subtlety...
and they fight
for hopeless causes, honor.
榮譽？
會害死幾百萬人，沒救過人
告訴你，我喜歡殺手，殺人成癖，出手乾淨俐落
真正的殺手拿到ZF1會問底座紅鈕的作用
帶教士上來
失樂園和飯店的情況打聽好了
幹得好，現在要想辦法去
有困難，班機客滿，明天有慈善晚會
因為名流雲集，飯店會戒備
一定有辦法
我去應門
要結婚？
Honor's killed millions of people.
Hasn't saved a single one.
I'll tell you what I do like:
a killer.
A dyed-in-the-wool killer,
cold-blooded, clean and methodical.
A real killer
picking up the ZF-1...
would've asked about the red button
on the bottom of the gun.
Bring me the priest.
I got everything we need
to know about Fhloston Paradise...
and a blueprint
of the hotel.
Good work, my son.
Now to find a way there.
It won't be easy.
There's a charity ball tomorrow.
Flights are full,
and the hotel will be guarded.
There must be a way.
I'll get it.
Weddings?
Not really.
不是吧？
- 卓格先生找你說話
- 誰？
卓格先生
- Mr. Zorg would like to talk to you.
- Who?
Mr. Zorg.
Jean-Baptiste...
尚巴迪斯
Emmanuel...
艾曼紐
卓格
很高興又見面了
我想起來了，你自稱是藝品商
你記起來最好，因為你需要它
那些石頭呢？
Zorg.
It's nice to see
you again, Father.
I remember you now.
The so-called art dealer.
I'm glad you got
your memory back.
Because you'll need it.
Where are the stones?
I don't know.
不知道，知道也不告訴你這種人
為什麼？我有什麼不對？
我努力救生命，你卻一心要毀滅生命
神父，你大錯特錯
聽我解釋
If I did, I wouldn't tell
someone like you.
Why?
What's wrong with me?
I try to serve life.
But you only...
want to destroy it.
Father...
you're so wrong.
Let me explain.
你侍奉的生命經由毀滅而混亂，譬如這空杯子
在這裡它是平靜的、無聊的，但是如果把它...
摧毀了
你看這些小東西，好忙碌，但每個都有用
多可愛的芭蕾舞，多采多姿
想想因這些機器人的製造，使技師、工程師得以養家活口
他們的子女長大後又生兒女，一直繁衍下去
為生命的大鏈子，貢獻力量
水
Life, which you so nobly serve,
comes from destruction and chaos.
Take this empty glass.
Here it is, peaceful...
boring.
But if it is...
destroyed.
Look at all these little things.
So busy now.
Notice how each is useful.
What a lovely ballet ensues...
so full of form and color.
Now think of all those people
that created them.
Technicians, engineers. People who
can feed their children tonight...
so those children can grow up
and have children...
and so on.
Thus adding
to the great chain...
of life.
Water. Fruit.
- 水果
- 神父，你看
- 我經由毀滅...
- 一顆櫻桃
來鼓舞生命
其實，我們是同行
乾杯
這時幫你捶背的機器人呢？
或是那工程師？
或是他們的子女？在哪？
你看，所有的權利並不可靠
你那專搞毀滅的帝國即將垮台了
只因為一粒小小的...櫻桃
你救我一命，為了回報，我也饒你
這一次
卓格，你好殘暴
我知道
你就算把總統打死我都不在乎
只要拿石頭來見我
限一個鐘頭
它在吞噬銀河系裡的衛星
為什麼它要吞噬衛星？
我們正在找答案
蒙族人哀慟意外，但是接受道歉
那些石頭，你找到沒？
You see, Father,
by creating a little destruction...
I'm encouraging life.
In reality,
you and I are in the same business.
Cheers.
Where's the robot
to pat you on the back?
Or the engineer?
Or their children, maybe?
There, you see how all your
so-called power counts for nothing?
How your entire empire
of destruction comes...
crashing down...
all because of one, little...
cherry.
You saved my life...
and in return,
I'll spare yours...
for now.
You're a monster, Zorg.
I know.
Torture who you have to,
the President, I don't care.
Just bring me the stones.
You have one hour.
It's gobbling up
all the satellites in the galaxy.
Why is it eating up
all the satellites?
We're working on it.
The Mondoshawan deplore the incident
but accept our apologies.
And the stones?
Did you find them?
They weren't on board.
- 不在船上
- 什麼？
蒙族一向不信任人類
把石頭交給別人
她叫狄娃，歌劇名角
幾小時後要在慈善晚會獻唱，石頭在她手中
What?
The Mondoshawan never
fully trusted the human race.
They gave them
to someone they do trust.
Her name is Plavalaguna.
She's a diva.
She's singing at a charity ball
in Fhloston Paradise.
She has the stones.
蒙族會幫忙
我們只要派人去取回石頭
好極了
這項行動要絕對保密，別動用軍隊
- 派頭號幹員秘密前去
- 我有最佳人選
你有信來
不看嗎？也許重要
像前兩封一樣重要
一封是老婆通知要離開我，一封是律師說跟我老婆私奔
The Mondoshawans will help.
We must send someone...
to get the stones.
Excellent.
I want this operation to be
as discreet as possible.
No troops.
No big operation.
I want your best man
to go undercover.
I have the perfect one.
You've got a message.
Not opening it?
Could be important.
Like the last two
were important.
First one was from my wife
telling me she's leaving.
The second was from my lawyer
telling me he was leaving with my wife.
真倒霉
我爺爺常說“不會天天下雨”，這次會是好事
賭你的午餐
好
快拿給我
“你被解雇了”
我很抱歉
（卓格）
That is bad luck.
Grandfather say...
"It never rain everyday."
This is good news, guaranteed.
I bet you lunch.
Okay.
Come on.
"You are fired."
Oh, I'm sorry.
At least I won lunch.
至少我贏到午餐
Good philosophy.
有道理
凡事往好處想，我喜歡
哈囉
See good in bad.
I like.
- Hello.
- Korben, sweetheart.
手指斷了嗎？不會撥電話給我
You got broken fingers?
You can't punch my number?
Hi, Mom.
- 媽，你好
- 我留了十七次話
別說機器壞了，它保用一千年
Seventeen messages.
Don't say your machine is broken again.
They last 1,000 years.
Mr. Kim,
you should go.
金先生，你先走吧！還要好一會兒
你給貓吃那麼好勝過愛我，不是貓養大你的，是我
再見，達先生
This'll take a minute.
You don't feed your cat a croquette,
who you love more than me.
She didn't breast-feed you.
I did.
Good fortune for you.
祝你好運連連
你沒有女朋友，我怎麼抱孫子？
這會給你添福的
希望如此
我身體不行了，這一趟要帶我
You don't have a girl.
I'll never be a grandmother.
It bring you good luck!
My body's failing.
Take me on this trip.
What are you
talking about?
你說什麼啊？
- 要我求你嗎？
- 不，我要你說明白
You want to make me beg?
No, all I want
is an explanation.
I just got in.
我剛進門，今天又撞車、又失業、又遭強盜
此外，一切都好，謝謝你的關心
別急，慢慢說清楚
你不知道你中獎了？免費到失樂園玩十天
你想把老媽丟在月球上嗎？
如果中獎我會知道，我會收到通知
電台廣播你名字一個鐘頭了
我再打給你
將軍，很高興在貧民區見到你
這公寓很不錯，少校，你過得很好嘛
聽說你失業了
你也知道了？
安啦！我找得到工作
不必麻煩，我們給你工作
- 達少校，你被選中出任務
- 什麼任務？
拯救世界
你到失樂園去，向狄娃拿四塊石頭回來
- 有問題嗎？
- 為何找我？我退伍半年了
有三個理由
第一，你在特種精英部隊精通各種武器和飛航器
第二，你的戰功最多
- 第三呢？
- 你是貴單位唯一的生還者
- 聽過答錄機沒？
- 今天的好事太多了
可能很要緊
你中獎了
你贏得比賽，可攜伴游失樂園
- 這是你的機票
- 你們操縱比賽？
恭喜你
- 就這麼公開嗎？
- 這一招最有效
艾少校假冒你太太同行
我不去
為什麼不？
將軍，失陪
什麼人？
是誰啊？
我太太
你再婚了？
對，不對，我要娶她，我愛她
但是她討厭部隊
她知道部隊曾經毀了我的婚姻
她要是看到你們會殺了我
快躲起來
幫幫忙
我們很願意，可是往哪躲？
- 少校，沒時間了
- 只要一下子，拜託
你們幫了大忙，我會婚姻幸福
- 少校...
- 幹嘛？
- 我們三個擠不下
- 可以
少校！
你踩到我的腳了...
- 真抱歉，華先生
- 是達先生
- 教士可以占別人便宜嗎？
- 我們有使命
什麼使命？
我們要拯救世界
- 憑你？要拯救世界？
- 是的
那一邊，那一邊
警方控制現場
這不是演習
快點進來，只待一分鐘，好嗎？
保證只要一分鐘
警方控制現場
- 不要碰任何東西
- 這不是演習
兩腿分開，雙手按住黃圈
- 你要幹嘛？
- 救你
這好像是一扇門，但是沒有門牌號碼
來看看
- 先生，你是人類嗎？
- 不是，我是肉製品的
我找到他了
達柯本先生
請你雙手按住黃圈
我要宰了你
答錯了
警方撤除控制
謝謝各位合作，祝各位愉快
我們捉到他了，好不容易
- 謝謝你的情報
- 我很樂意幫忙
這個人因為走私鈾被捕
現在我只要冒充他去機場，四小時後就可以到失樂園
沒拿到石頭不要回來
- 我們捉到柯本了
- 好極了
艾卡尼，你接手去失樂園拿石頭
卓格要是真的想要，就會來談判，我們就可以報仇了
真抱歉，我忘了自動洗
蓮蓬有自動洗裝置
我很抱歉
- 自...動...洗
- 自動洗，蓮蓬有自動洗
奇怪，一天遇到你兩次，兩次你都落在我懷裡
今天是我的幸運日
幸...運...日
- 你聽到聲音沒有？
- 柯維多
自動洗
- 很抱歉
- 我不要你幫忙
- 喝杯咖啡？
- 好，謝謝
自動洗
我不擅長沖咖啡
神父喝咖啡這麼凶
我知道不光彩，但是沒辦法
我接受這項任務
- 弄到沒有？
- 有
- 達麗露
- 多國通行證
達柯本大衛，好
我冒充你丈夫嫌太老，大衛的身體...情況很好
找狄娃拿石頭，再到埃及找我
現在就去，拜託
好
最後呼叫前往失樂園
最後呼叫前往失樂園，請快點
這是機票
請出示身份證
對不起
- 插進去
- 這裡嗎？
達先生
恭喜你贏得比賽
是啊！對
抱歉，一團亂
- 亂？
- 那些垃圾
趕上了
我怕趕不上，所以叫大衛幫我拿登機證
現在大衛可以走了，謝謝你，再見
我是達柯本
如有違規，請立刻報告
那這位是？
達麗露，多國通行證
- 多國通行證
- 多國通行證，她知道
我太太，剛認識就結婚
你知道，兩個相撞會產生火花，她知道
總之我們相愛了
我知道她雖被造得很剛強，但她也有脆弱有人性，懂嗎？
還要酒嗎？
來兩杯
- 麗露呢？
- 跟達先生登機了
什麼？
抱歉，當時我沒辦法，我怕他殺了我
這不可能
- 怎麼會這樣？
- 再來一杯嗎？
都怪我不好，不該把自己的使命交給你
我知道
- 這是廟門的鑰匙
- 慘了
準備去埃及，我要面對命運
我不要去埃及
達先生？達柯本
我就是
請等一下
(非常危險）
再等一下就好了
我們馬上回來
達先生，我們現在需要你
魯比羅要在現場訪問你
小姐
多國通行證
告訴阿克諾，改用B計劃
前面有異形，散開
支援單位，18區
（危險禁區）
魯比是廣播巨星，上他的節目真光榮
他酷斃了
我相信你很興奮
我是來度假不想被打擾，我寧可默默無聞
柯本，達柯本
雙子星大賽優勝者來了
他火力十足，女士們融化吧！
他熱上加熱，他辣斃了
身材標準、髮型出眾，帥呆了
酷斃了，他有話要說
要對五百億雙耳朵說
說啊！酷哥
嗨
真是酷斃了
顫慄吧！他要在世界點火
從五點到七點，酷哥的事都要告訴你們
他的夢想，他的慾望
他最、最隱秘的私事
看起來，他令人迷戀
兄弟
你服役時緊張嗎？
不緊張
注意，柯本在此上節目
昨天的青蛙會變成明天的王子
失樂園的王子
一千零一支棒棒糖
魔幻山有美酒、美女
以及通宵狂歡
徹夜不眠，通宵達旦
快告訴媽媽這裡有帥哥
五點到七點，我為你報導
追蹤今年度最性感的酷哥
我的夥伴
- 廣播結束
- 明天五點見
節目怎麼樣？
我看你酷斃了
酷的像什麼？
酷得透頂，要多酷有多酷
親愛的，你覺得呢？太爛了，太無聊了
別死氣沉沉，你正在上節目
一定要讓人興奮
明天上節目，不要打不出一個屁來
一定要酷，好嗎？
借一步說話，好嗎？
我不受你擺布
所以明天的節目你自己玩，酷不酷？
超級酷
- 達先生，達柯本
- 就是我
只有一位達柯本，已經報到了
不可能，我才是達柯本
抱歉，登機結束了
等一下，等等
我要抗議，真沒道理
這不是演習，由警方控制
- 對不起
- 把雙手放在黃色園圈中
是我弄錯了，弄錯了
為了縮短旅程，我們會開啟催眠裝置
讓您在飛行中入睡
謝謝
- 嗨！
- 你會講英語了
- 我學了
- 很好
我們不是來度假，我有重要任務，幫要人做事
我要是不來你會有麻煩，懂嗎？
懂嗎？大麻煩
懂
但是你，沒麻煩
我，第五元素，是神人
我，保護你
睡吧！
- 達先生，祝你好夢
- 等等...
機長，第一區催眠啟動
第二區啟動了沒？
第二區？
機長，都準備好了
- 羅先生
- 幹嘛？
請維持坐姿
我會所有的姿勢
羅先生
起落架有寄生蟲
- 地勤人員，聽到沒？
- 聽到了，起落架
夥計，給我火
我們這裡需要火，弄點火來
弄點火來這裡
天啊！弄點火來這裡
（警報）
謝謝，真多謝
過來...給我...
你活該
羅先生
叫我魯比
加油準備出發
我請你喝一杯
你已經起飛了？
我不在班機上
什麼？
他本人取代我
我搞不懂
你在說笑嗎？
不是，我發誓是真的，我跟人類從未有過這種感覺
真的嗎？
對
我用盡辦法也登不了機
- 地面清除
- 準備起飛？
確定
不要，求求你，不要碰那裡
- 氣壓？
- 好了
- 防護盾？
- 確定
動力加強
十秒
我...有一點...
失望
五
我最不喜歡的事
三
就是...
二
失望
一
我知道
起飛了
- 起落架還原
- 檢查光速運作
（無線電通訊）
（計算中）
終於有聯絡了
它發出無線電波
它為什麼發電波？
也許它正在呼叫
卓格辦公室
我說過別打擾我
我知道，除非是影子先生，而影子先生正在線上
影子又來了
我是卓格
我打擾你了嗎？
沒有，我只是在...
你在哪？
在不遠處
很好，很好
我們的石頭怎麼樣？
好，還好
我隨時可以取到你要的石頭，但是不容易
我的開銷增加三倍
錢不是問題，不要緊
我...要...那些石頭
沒問題，我會親自去辦
不久之後，我會到你們那裡
- 斷掉了
- 通訊斷掉了
可惡
我們開始降臨失樂園了
當地時間是下午3點20分，當地溫度華氏85度
祝您旅途愉快，期待您再次搭乘
對不起，謝謝
主通風管有寄生蟲
又有？我去處理
我們到了沒？
- 到了
- 好極了
本店有十二座游泳池，屋頂有兩座
餐廳都在第二到第十層之間
園裡有四百個沙灘，開放到5點
然後飛船會升高，帶你看美景
- 狄娃來了沒？
- 還沒
還有票嗎？
第一排留了你的位子，在魯比旁邊
他好有才藝，我愛死他了
他有你的票，廿分鐘後會到
哪有衣服買？
達先生，祝你愉快
謝謝
找哪位？
小雜種，真不該把你生出來
媽？
我生你吃盡苦頭，你這樣回報我
還不如養電子雞
別鬧了
我比你更應該來，我要曬黑，我要喝雞尾酒
把箱子拿進去
狄娃小姐，我叫霧
歡迎光臨，我是...
安全人員，歡迎...
你真高
- 借一步說話
- 好的
- 你叫什麼名字？
- 霧
狄娃小姐，很高興你來了，散場後她會把東西交給你
無線太空台，現在是下午5點
- 舵轉108度
- 是
主持人魯比羅和幸運的優勝者，達柯本
雙子星大賽的贏家
來在失樂園現場的直播
天堂
魯比陪伴你兩小時
還有柯本和飯店經理
以及雙子星小姐和八千位幸運的贏家
在此欣賞狄娃出眾的演出
現在我們堂堂進入宇宙最華麗的歌劇院
古典歌劇院完美的複製
沒人在乎吧！
我右邊坐一排大官，很神氣
左邊坐著影劇巨星，貝比雷
他耳聾，音樂對他沒啥作用
要給誰？
還有雷射球王，洛方培根
柯達王和可愛的公主，最近她跟我說喜歡唱歌
對了，我錄了她美妙的歌聲
待會兒再放，現在請柯本講話
夥伴，來到大世界高興嗎？
高興死了
現在...開香檳酒
上廣告！上廣告！
休息三十秒
好戲登場了
有艘船拿不到停靠許可
停在船塢裡，通知安全處
准許停泊一小時
綽綽有餘了
什麼事？
來為狄娃開香檳
來了！
我找到箱子了
捉住她
剛才中了埋伏
既然他們要打，就跟他們拼了
好精采，精采
精采，小姐，我佩服你
謝謝代勞，我做也不過如此
把石頭交給我
不準動，我要這艘船
手舉起來
這音樂我熟
來換個節拍吧！
我們被攻擊了
到處都有他們，我看到一個戰士了，好醜
頭大如鬥，還長獠牙，醜死了
是孟加羅人
政府派我來協助你
有人聽到的話，來第一排找我
你要把石頭交給她
- 誰？
- 第五元素
奉命來地球拯救宇宙的神人
- 麗露？
- 是的
可是她看起來軟弱不堪
她需要你的幫忙，需要你的愛
要不然，她會死掉
不，醒一醒
救命
如果要把事情做好，就得自己動手
拜託，你不能死
醒醒，石頭在哪？
- 什麼？
- 石頭在哪？
那些石頭...
不在這裡
石頭在哪？
在我裡面
什麼？
我的天，柯本，又來一個
我們走吧！柯本...
等一下，再等一下
你！
我在叫你
- 我不是跟他一夥的
- 其他人呢？
我說等一下，魯比，拿著這把槍
- 什麼？你要我做什麼？
- 拿著這把槍
- 用手拿著，拿好
- 天啊
他動，你就射他
我覺得不對勁，很不對勁，柯本
石頭在我裡面
我頭好疼，不太對勁
魯比？
對不起...
他要不要緊？
天啊！柯本，又來一個
慘了，來了三個
聽好！
你要拼老命保護這些石頭，否則會跟他一樣，了解嗎？
了解
- 你確定嗎？
- 確定
這就是你說的萬無一失？
放心，我了解我的人，他會平定天下
移動！快！
我的天，各位先生女士，真是奇觀
讓我來
我的天，我的優勝者柯本有難了
雷！
槍！
把槍丟給我，給我槍
我要過去，試著能不能靠近一點看
對，那把槍，對了
謝了，雷
別開槍，我沒有武器
- 起來
- 你認錯人了，別開槍
我沒有武器
我的天
我是來度假的，不要開槍打我
我贏得...
有獎比賽
雙子星提供的失樂園之旅
下來
等一下
他想說話
下來
對不起，夥伴
柯本...你在哪？
我的天！天啊！
柯本，他們來了，他們來了
柯本！
- 不要動
- 什麼？
那是什麼？
數到十
- 柯本
- 幹嘛？
- 是不是炸彈？
- 閉嘴，快點數
一、二、三、四、五
六、七、八
九
十
我非常地失望
柯本，你在找什麼？
控制室
“控制室”
- 就是這裡
- 我走這邊
一起來
安靜，安靜
- 你負責這裡？
- 對
外面有幾個？
- 不知道
- 數數看
左邊七個，右邊五個
右邊四個，左邊兩個
找首領，沒有首領就打不起來
再開一槍，我們就殺人質
- 那就是首領
- 派人來談判
我...我不會談判
不介意我試一試吧？
好啊！當然好
我們派人來談判了
還有誰要談判？
那...那種談判在哪學的？
我也很想知道
魯比主人？
我以為他死了
主人
小意思，舉手之勞
各位，魯比羅還活著
搞什麼？會痛
我知道你一定很氣我
我是替天行道
你要拯救世界，我想起來了
現在我只想救麗露
她有難？
麗露哪天沒有難？
那裡，那是哪？
狄娃的套房
麗露？
撐下去
你怎麼弄得這麼慘？
有我在，不要緊，沒事了
聽我說
我拿到石頭了，別激動
夥伴，這東西怎麼有號碼？
是，是...
不對，不對...
如果這是炸彈，飯店的偵測器就會發警報
對嗎？
這是緊急警報，基於安全理由，飯店內要疏散
- 請大家前往救生艇...
- 保持鎮定
請鎮定
小心
柯本，你一定會拆這種東西，對不對？
柯本？
兩分鐘內完成疏散
- 退回去
- 疏散，疏散
你不能留下來，飯店裡有炸彈
我知道
我不想死！
拜託，別亂叫
快進去
一分鐘內完成疏散
走這邊
四十五秒
把她固定在位子上
柯本，柯本大哥
你會開這東西吧？
就像開計程車
有門我們怎麼出去？
十五秒
十、九、八...
七、六、五...
吾族萬歲！
完了！
坐穩了
就像開計程車
各位，現在是晚上7點
明天將會有更精采的冒險
廣播結束
這是我最精采的報導
總統先生，達少校拿到五種元素了
教士直接帶他們去那座寺廟
我們得救了
狄娃說我應該照顧你
人類行事好奇怪
什麼意思？
你們造的東西都有毀滅作用
這叫天性，你從電腦學的嗎？
還沒學完，只看到V部
V是好字母，V部有些好字
什麼字？
英勇的
脆弱的
非常美的
當然了，蒙洛
總統先生
現在又怎麼了？
我...
我們有難題了
你說它在逼近是什麼意思？
不但逼近，而且快的不得了，我們正在試圖追蹤
你知道它朝什麼方向嗎？
柯本，有將軍打電話來
我幫你接總統
達少校，我首先要向勇士致敬
- 你是軍人的楷模
- 總統先生
我代表聯邦...
請說重點好嗎？
直徑一千兩百英里的火球衝向地球
問題嚴重，我們束手無策
還有多少時間？
照這速度，1小時57分
我2小時後再回電
喂？喂？
“戰爭”
他們降落在沙漠上了
大衛，幹得好
- 把她放在中央
- 放哪？這裡嗎？
你想出來了沒？
這塊應該是“火”
你會擺石頭陣嗎？
- 理論上會
- 理論上？
四塊石頭應該在周圍
第五元素應該在中央
武器就會有效
- 你沒看過實際布陣？
- 沒有
給我
武器都有手冊，這個一定也有
對，跟圖形吻合，快點
風
- 你在幹嘛？老兄
- 什麼？
你在幹嘛啊？
想辦法保住你的工作
火
- 成了
- 現在呢？
現在要打開石頭
你會打開吧？
理論上...
不會
麗露，醒醒，你得幫我們
你怎麼打開這些石頭？
風吹
火燒
這我懂，可是怎麼打開？
雨...
淋
麗露，麗露
什麼意思？
我認為是...
也許是猜字謎
或者是某種遊戲
五分鐘內打不開，我們就會死
- 死？
- 對，死
來不及了
通訊中斷了
三分鐘
我的破了，為什麼給我破的？
永遠打不開了
柯本，它動了
- 你做了什麼？再做一遍
- 什麼都沒做
別吵，別吵
冷靜點，做給我看
- 我本來站在這裡...
- 然後呢？
然後我手按在上面說
永遠打不開了
就這樣？
柯本？
風，她說風吹
每人選一塊石頭
水澆水、火點火、土撤土，快
土
- 去選另一塊
- 好
柯本...
柯本...我沒有火
我沒有火柴，你有嗎？
知道我就不戒煙了，神父，你抽煙嗎？
有火柴嗎？我們需要火
我們死定了
暫時屏氣
一分鐘
麗露，醒醒，快醒醒
該輪到你上場了
保衛生命
至死方休
麗露，聽我說，聽我說
聽著，我知道你很累
辦完事以後我帶你去度假
真正的度假，就我們兩個
你現在要是不出手的話，我們都會死
你們在殺生，拯救生命有什麼意義？
四十秒後進入大氣層
你說得對
但是有些事，美好的事值得拯救
美好的事，美好的...
像是愛嗎？
對，對，愛！說得好
愛值得拯救
我只會保護，不會愛
除此以外，我一無是處
我需要你，非常需要你
因為...
告訴她啊！柯本
求求你...告訴我
為什麼需要我
因為...
告訴我
因為我愛你，我愛你
十、九...
八、七...
六、五...
四、三...
二...
一
只差六十二英里就撞上了
你叫什麼叫？
每隔五分鐘就有新的狀況
I just smashed my cab.
I lost my job. I got mugged.
Besides that,
everything's peachy.
Thanks for asking.
Now settle down
and explain this to me.
You don't know
you won a trip...
to Fhloston Paradise for two
for ten days?
I suppose you'll just leave me
on the lunar surface?
If I'd won a trip,
I'd know.
I would've been notified.
They've been blaring your name out
on the radio for an hour.
I'll call you back.
General, how nice to see you
in the 5000 block.
Nice apartment.
You've settled
into a wonderful life.
Heard you lost your job.
You heard that?
Don't worry.
I'll get another job.
Don't bother.
We have one for you.
"Major Dallas...
you've been selected
for a mission."
- What mission?
- To save the world.
"You leave
for Fhloston Paradise.
Get four stones from the diva
Plavalaguna and bring them back."
Any questions?
Why me? I retired
six months ago. Remember?
Three reasons.
One:
As a member
of the Elite Special Forces Unit...
you are an expert in the use of
all necessary weapons and spacecraft.
Two: You're the most highly
decorated member of your unit.
The third?
Of all the members of your unit,
you're the only one left alive.
Check your messages?
I've had enough good news.
Might be important.
You're a winner!
You've won the Gemini Contest
and a trip to Fhloston Paradise for two.
Here are your tickets.
You rigged the contest?
Congratulations.
You couldn't
be more discreet?
Old tricks are the best tricks.
Major Iceborg will
accompany you as your wife.
I am not going.
Why not?
Excuse me, General.
Who is it?
My wife.
You remarried?
Yes... no. I just met this girl,
but I'm going to marry her.
I love her,
but she hates the military.
She knows the military
ruined my last marriage.
She can't have anything
to do with it.
If she sees you,
she'll kill me.
- Major--
- You gotta hide somewhere.
You've gotta help me.
We'd love to,
but where can we hide?
We don't
have time for this.
It's just for one minute.
You have no idea
how much you're helping me.
No idea--
You have no idea.
- I'm going to be happily married.
- Major! Major!
- The three of us won't fit.
- Sure you will.
Major!
You're on my foot.
Major! Major!
I'm really sorry to resort to this,
Mr. Wallace--
Dallas.
We heard about your good luck
and need your tickets for Fhloston.
Is this the way
priests vacation?
We're on a mission.
What kind?
We have to save
the world, my son.
You're gonna
save the world?
Yes!
Down there.
This is a police control.
This is not an exercise.
Come on, get in.
For one minute, all right?
Just stay here
for one minute.
- This is a police control.
- Don't touch anything.
This is not an exercise.
Can you please spread your legs...
and place your hands
in the yellow circles.
- What are you doing?
- Saving you so you can save the world.
Yeah, but I--
I think this is the door.
No name, no number.
Let's see it.
Are you classified
as human?
Negative.
I am a meat Popsicle.
I found him.
Mr. Korben Dallas?
Sir, can you put your hands
in the yellow circles, please?
Smoke you!
Wrong answer.
The police control
is now terminated.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Have a nice day.
We got the guy.
Wasn't easy but we bagged him.
- Thanks for the tip.
- Glad to be of help, my friend.
The guy's been arrested
for uranium smuggling.
All I have to do now is go
to the airport, take his place...
and I'll be in Fhloston
in four hours.
Don't come back
without the stones.
We got Korben Dallas.
Perfect.
Akanit, take command.
Go to Fhloston
and get the stones.
If Zorg really wants them...
he'll have to negotiate.
Revenge is at hand.
Oh, I am so sorry.
I forgot
about the autowash.
There's an autowash
in that shower.
I'm so sorry.
Autowash.
Autowash, yes.
Autowash, in the shower.
It's funny.
I've met you twice today.
Both times
you've ended up in my arms.
It's my lucky day.
Lucky day.
Did you hear something?
Cornelius.
Autowash.
- I'm so sorry.
- I don't need your help.
- Want a cup of coffee?
- Yes, please.
Autowash.
Coffee's not my specialty.
But you must drink a lot
of coffee being a priest.
I know. I'm not proud of what I did.
I had no choice.
I'll take the mission.
- Did you get them?
- Yeah.
Good.
- "Leeloo Dallas."
- "Multi-pass."
"Korben David Dallas."
Perfect.
I can't be your husband.
I'm too old.
Now David is...
in great shape.
he'll protect you.
Now, please, go to the Diva, collect
the stones and meet me at the temple.
Now. Yes.
Okay.
Last call for Fhloston Paradise.
Hurry.
The tickets.
- ID, please.
- I'm sorry.
- There.
- In here?
Mr. Dallas?
Congratulations on the contest.
Oh, right. Okay.
- Sorry for the mess.
- The mess?
The garbage.
Made it!
I was afraid
I wouldn't make it...
so I sent David
to pick up my boarding pass.
Now David must go.
Thank you. Bye.
I am Korben Dallas.
Please report infractions
immediately to the spaceport.
And this is?
Leeloo Dallas.
Multi-pass.
She knows
it's a multi-pass.
My wife.
We're newlyweds. Just met.
Bump into each other, sparks happen--
She knows.
Anyway, we're in love.
I mean, I know
she's made to be strong.
She's also so fragile, so human.
You know what I mean?
- You want more?
- Yeah.
Make that two.
- Where's Leeloo?
- On the plane with Mr. Dallas.
What!
I didn't know
what to do.
But this is not possible.
This is not possible.
You want some more?
This is all my fault.
It is my mission.
I shouldn't have given it to you.
I know.
- The key to the temple.
- Oh, no.
Prepare for our arrival.
I go to face my destiny.
I don't want
to go to Egypt.
Dallas?
Korben Dallas?
That's me.
Just a minute, please.
It will just take
one more minute.
We'll be right back.
Mr. Dallas...
we really need you now.
Ruby Rhod is broadcasting live
and needs to interview you.
Multi-pass.
Tell Aknot that plan A flopped.
Go to plan B.
Aliens ahead.
Spread out.
Backup unit, zone 18.
Ruby Rhod is the biggest radio star.
It's an honor to be on his talk show.
He's so green.
I'm sure you're excited.
I'm on vacation
and don't want to be bothered.
I prefer to remain anonymous.
Korben Dallas!
Here he is! The winner of
the Gemini Croquette Contest.
This boy is fuelled like fire,
so start melting, ladies...
'cause he is hotter than hot.
He's hot, hot, hot!
The right size, the right build,
the right hair, the right on.
Right on.
And he's got
something to say...
to those 50 billion pairs of ears
out there.
Pop it, D-man.
Hi.
Unbelievable.
Quiver, ladies.
He's going to set the world on fire.
Right here
from five to seven.
You'll know everything
there is to know about the D-man.
His dreams...
his desires...
his most intimates of intimates.
And from what I'm looking at,
intimate is his middle name.
So tell me, my man...
you nervous in the service?
Not really.
Freeze those knees 'cause Korben's
in the place and he's on the case.
Yesterday's frog
will be tomorrow's Prince...
of Fhloston Paradise!
The hotel of a thousand and one
follies and lollies.
A magic fountain flowing
with nonstop wine, women and...
hootchie-kootchie-koo...
all night long.
All night long
All night
Start licking stamps, girls, because
he'll have you writing home to Mama.
Here from five to seven,
I'll be your voice, your tongue.
On the trail of the sexiest
man of the year: D-man, your man...
my man.
End of transmission.
See you tomorrow at five.
How was it?
It was just absolutely green.
Green like what?
Crystal green.
Any kind of green
you want...
tree green, emerald,
pond green.
Korben, sweetheart, what was that?
It was bad! It had nothing!
No fire! No energy!
I have a show to run here.
It must pop, pop, pop!
So tomorrow, from five to seven...
please act like you have
more than a two-word vocabulary.
It must be green!
Okay? Okay?
Can I talk to you for a second?
Just talk to you?
I didn't come here to play
Pumba on the radio.
Tomorrow, from five to seven,
you'll give yourself a hand.
Green?
Super green.
Dallas? Korben Dallas?
That's me.
I only have one Korben Dallas
on my list, and he's checked in.
That's impossible.
I am Korben Dallas.
Sorry, sir.
Boarding is finished.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait!
I need to talk
to someone!
I don't believe this!
This is not an exercise.
This is a police control.
I'm sorry. I'm calm.
There's been a mistake.
To make your flight short...
flight attendants are switching
on the sleep regulator...
which will regulate your sleeping
during the flight.
Thank you.
Hi.
- You speak English.
- Yes. I learn.
Good.
We are not on vacation.
I'm on an important mission.
I work for some important people.
If I hadn't come to get you,
you'd be in trouble.
Understand?
Yes.
But you, no trouble.
Me, Fifth Element.
Supreme Being.
Me protect you.
Sleep.
Sweet dreams,
Mr. Dallas.
Sleep regulator operative
in zone one.
Thank you.
Are you operative?
Zone two?
Everything's ready, Captain.
What?
Assume your
individual position.
But I want all positions!
Mr. Rhod--
Parasites in landing gear.
Ground, copy?
Got it.
Front gear.
Hey, man,
give me some heat, man!
We need some heat here!
Get some heat!
Some heat over here, man!
Good shit, man.
Put the heat over here!
Thank you!
Thank you very much!
Come, come.
Give me this. Give me this.
Take that.
Mr. Rhod!
You can call me Ruby.
Fueled and ready to go.
I'll buy you one.
Taken off already?
I'm not on the plane.
What?
The real Dallas
took my place.
I don't understand.
Are you making fun of me?
No, no, no!
I swear! I swear!
I never felt this way before
with a human.
Really?
I've tried everything.
There's no way to get on the plane.
Ground is clear.
Ready for liftoff?
Confirmed.
Not there. No, please, not there.
Please, not there.
- Power pressure?
- Primed.
- Protection?
- Confirmed.
Power increase.
Ten seconds.
I am...
a little...
disappointed.
5...
If there is one thing
I do not like...
3...
it is to be...
2...
disappointed.
1...
Sorry, it will
never happen again.
I know.
Liftoff.
- Landing gear secure.
- Checklist for light speed.
We're finally
getting something.
It's sending
radio wavelengths.
What does it want
with radio waves?
Maybe it wants
to make a call.
Zorg's office.
I told you I did not
want to be disturbed.
You don't want to be disturbed
except if it's Mr. Shadow...
and Mr. Shadow's
on the line.
It's Shadow again.
Zorg here.
Am I disturbing you?
No, no, I was just--
Where are you?
Not far now.
Good.
Good, good.
How are the stones?
Fine. Fine.
Just fine.
I'll have the four stones
you asked for any time now...
but it wasn't easy.
My costs have tripled.
Money is of no...
importance.
I...
want...
the stones.
The stones...
will be here.
I'll see to it
personally.
I will be among you...
soon.
We lost it.
We lost the signal.
Damn!
We've begun our descent
toward Fhloston Paradise.
The local time
is 3:20 p.m.
Auto-temperature is currently
85 degrees Fahrenheit.
We hope you enjoyed your flight
and hope to see you again soon.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to paradise.
Excuse me, dear. Excuse me.
Excuse me, please.
Parasites in the main ventilation.
Again?
I'll get it.
Have we arrived yet?
Oh, good.
We have twelve swimming pools
and two on the rooftop.
All the restaurants
are between levels two and ten.
The planet Fhloston has 400 beaches,
all accessible until 5 p.m...
then the airship goes higher...
to offer you a better view.
Is the Diva here?
Not yet.
Any tickets left
for the opera?
You have a seat reserved,
front row...
next to Ruby Rhod!
He's so talented.
I love him. He's so sexy.
He has your ticket,
and he'll be here in 20 minutes.
Where can I get
something to wear?
- Enjoy your evening, Mr. Dallas.
- Thank you.
You miserable bastard,
I never should've pushed you out.
I was in labor for days,
and this is how you repay me?
I should've gotten
a robot.
Come on, Ma.
I should be there, not you.
I need a tan.
I need a cocktail.
Get the case in.
Hello, Ms. Diva.
I'm Fog.
Welcome to the--
I'm security.
Tall.
- Can I talk to you?
- Sure. Yeah.
- What's your name?
- Fog.
Ms. Plavalaguna is glad
that you are here.
She'll give you what you've come
to get after the concert.
Stay here.
You're listening to Radio Cosmos.
It is 5 p.m.
Helm to 108.
Helm 108!
Time to join Ruby Rhod...
and Korben Dallas,
the lucky winner...
of the Gemini Croquette contest.
Coming at you live
from Fhloston...
Paradise!
Ruby Rhod at your service with Korben
and the manager of this hotel...
and Miss Gemini Croquette
in person...
and 8,000 other lucksters here...
to enjoy the privilege of
the unique concert of Miss Plavalaguna!
Now we enter what must be...
the most beautiful concert hall
of all the universe!
A perfect replica
of an old opera house...
but who cares?
To my right, a row of ministers,
more sinisters than ministers.
To my left, Baby Ray,
star of stage and screen.
He's not going to get much
out of this concert. He's stone-deaf!
To who?
And here we have Roy Von Baker,
king of laser ball.
The Emperor of Kodar Japhet
and his lovely daughter.
"I love to sing,"
she recently confessed to me.
By the way, I have a recording
of her talented voice.
I'll play the rest after the concert.
Now it's time...
for Korben to say
the word of the day.
Tell me, my man, you happy
here in the big world?
Thrilled.
And now...
champagne!
Commercial!
Break for 30 seconds.
Show time.
I have a ship in trouble
requesting permission to dock.
Put him in the docking garage.
Inform security.
- Permission granted for one hour.
- More than I need.
Champagne for the Diva.
I'll take it.
I found it.
Get her!
It was an ambush.
If it's war they want...
it's war they'll get!
Bravo! Bravo!
My compliments, little lady.
Thank you for doing
the dirty work.
I couldn't have done
a better job myself.
Hand over the stones.
Nobody move!
I'm taking over the ship!
Hands up!
I know this music.
Let's change the beat.
I think we're
being attacked.
They're everywhere.
I see one of them.
They're warriors, and they're ugly.
They got big teeth, and they got
big foreheads, and they stink.
Mangalores.
The government
sent me to help you.
If somebody hears this,
come and get me.
I'm in the first row.
You must give her the stones.
Who?
The Fifth Element.
The Supreme Being sent to Earth
to save the universe.
Leeloo?
But she's more fragile
than she seems.
She needs your help...
and your love...
or...
she will die.
Stay with me.
Help!
If you want
something done...
do it yourself.
Come on, honey.
You can't die.
Wake up!
Where are the stones?
The stones.
They're not here.
The stones,
where are they?
In me.
What?
Oh, my God, Korben.
Korben, another one coming.
- I think we should go.
- One minute. One minute.
Hey, you!
I said you.
- I'm not with him.
- Where's the other?
I said, "one minute."
Ruby, hold this gun.
What do you
want me to do?
Come on.
Put your hand
on it.
- What do I do?
- If he moves, squeeze the trigger.
I don't feel right.
- I don't feel right.
- The stones are "in me."
I got a headache.
This ain't me.
Sorry.
Think he'll be okay?
Oh, my God, Korben.
Another one coming.
Shit. Three coming.
You guard this
with your life...
or you'll look like him.
You green?
Green.
Super green?
Is that your idea
of a discreet operation?
Don't worry. I know my man.
He'll calm things down.
Move! Move!
Oh, my God.
Ladies and gentlemen...
this is amazing.
Let me do it.
Oh, my God.
Korben Dallas, my man,
is in trouble.
The gun!
Give me the gun.
I'm going to go...
and try to see if I can see
something a little closer.
Yes, the gun. Yeah.
Thanks, Ray.
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
I'm not armed!
Get up!
You've got the wrong guy!
Don't shoot!
I'm not armed.
Oh, my God.
I'm on vacation.
Don't shoot me, please.
I'm on a vacation.
I won a...
contest.
Gemini Croquette's to...
Fhloston Paradise.
Down.
Wait a minute.
Get down!
He's trying
to say something.
Down!
Sorry, my man.
Where are you?
Oh, my God.
They're coming.
Don't move.
What you doing?
Count to ten.
- Was that a bomb?
- Shut up and count!
3! 4! 5!
6...
7, 8...
9...
10.
I am...
very disappointed.
Korben, what are you
looking for?
Control room.
- This is it.
- I'll be here.
Let's go.
Quiet! Quiet!
You in charge?
How many
are out there?
- I don't know.
- Let's count.
Seven on the left.
Five on the right.
Four on the right.
Two on the left.
Find the leader.
They won't fight without the leader.
One more shot and we start
killing hostages.
That's the leader.
Send someone to negotiate.
I've never negotiated.
You mind if I try?
We're sending
somebody to negotiate.
Anybody else
want to negotiate?
Where did he learn
to negotiate like that?
I wonder.
Where's Ruby?
I thought he was dead.
Master!
It was nothing, really.
Just a helping hand.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Ruby Rhod...
still alive.
What's wrong with you?
It hurt!
I realize that you must be
pretty mad at me...
but I'm fighting
for a noble cause.
Yes, you're trying to save the world.
I remember.
Right now,
I'm trying to save Leeloo.
Leeloo's in trouble?
When is Leeloo
not in trouble?
- Where's that?
- The Diva's suite.
Hang on.
Here, come on.
How do you get yourself
into these positions?
Come on.
I'm here. It's all right.
Everything's okay now.
Listen.
I got the stones.
Just take it easy, all right?
My man, my man, what's this thing
with all these numbers?
If it was a bomb...
the alarms would go off because
all these hotels have bomb detectors.
This is a type "A" alert.
For security reasons,
the hotel must be evacuated.
Proceed calmly
to the lifeboats...
Stay calm!
...located in the main hallways.
You know how to stop this,
right?
Two minutes
to complete evacuation.
Get back!
Evacuation!
Sorry, you can't stay here.
There's a bomb in the hotel.
I know.
I don't want to die.
Please, my son.
Get in.
One minute to total evacuation.
This one.
45 seconds.
Get her strapped in.
You know how to fly this?
Like driving a cab.
How will we
get out the door?
15 seconds.
10...
9, 8...
7...
6...
5.
For the honor.
Hold on.
Like driving a cab.
It is now 7 p.m.,
time for the news.
See you tomorrow
for a new adventure.
End of transmission.
That's the best show
I ever did.
Major Dallas has
the five elements on board...
and the priest is guiding them
to the temple.
We're saved.
The Diva said
I should take care of you.
Humans act so strange.
What do you mean?
Everything you created...
is used to destroy.
We call it human nature.
You learn that
on your screen?
I'm not finished yet.
I'm up to "V."
"V" is good.
Some good words in "V."
Like what?
"Valiant."
"Vulnerable."
"Very beautiful."
Oh, of course, Munro!
Mr. President?
Now what?
We have a problem.
It's advancing?
It's not only advancing,
it's moving at incredible speed.
And do you have any idea
where it's heading?
Korben, there's
a general on the phone.
I'll give you
the President.
Major Dallas, I first
would like to salute a warrior.
You're a shining example
of this army.
In the name
of the Federation--
Any idea when you'll
get to the point?
A ball of fire 1,200 miles in diameter
heading straight for earth...
and we have no idea how to stop it.
That's the problem.
How much time do we have?
If its speed remains constant,
in an hour and 57 minutes.
I'll call you back
in two hours.
Hello?
They just landed
in the desert.
Good job, David.
- Put her in the center.
- Where? Here?
You got it figured out, Father?
This one should be fire.
- You know how this works?
- Theoretically.
The four stones
should go around.
The Fifth Element should be
in the middle...
and then the weapon
against evil should work.
You've never seen this work?
Give me that.
Every weapon has a manual.
I'm sure this has one too.
That's it.
Match up the symbols.
Go! Go!
Wind.
My man, what you doing?
- What?
- What you doing?
Trying to keep you
in the D.J. business.
Fire.
Done.
What happens?
So, now,
we have to open them.
And you know how to do that.
Right?
Theoretically...
No.
Leeloo, honey, wake up.
You have to help us.
How do you open the stones?
Wind blows.
Fire burns.
Yes, I know all that.
But how do you open these stones?
Rain...
falls.
What does it mean?
I think that--
Maybe it's a charade.
A game or something.
If we don't get these stones open
in five minutes, we're dead.
- Dead?
- Yes, dead.
Too late.
We've lost contact with them.
Three minutes.
I think mine is broken.
Why I gotta get
the broke one?
We're never gonna make it.
It moved.
- Show me what you did.
- Nothing.
Shut up, shut up!
Show me what you did,
step-by-step.
- I was standing here.
- Quickly.
I put my hands on the top
like this, and I said...
"We're not going to make it."
And that's it?
Korben, my man.
Wind.
She said, "Wind blows."
Everyone take a stone.
Water for water. Fire for fire.
Earth for Earth. Go!
Earth.
Open the other one.
Korben, my man,
I have no fire.
I have no matches.
Do you have any?
I stopped smoking.
Father, you smoke?
Got some matches?
We need some fire.
We're going to die.
Don't breathe.
Fire.
One minute.
Let's go, Leeloo.
Wake up. Wake up.
It's time for you to work now.
Protect life...
until death.
Listen to me!
Listen to me.
Listen,
I know you're very tired.
I'll take you on vacation.
A real vacation, just you and me.
But if you don't
do something right now...
we'll all die.
What's the use of saving life
when you see what you do with it?
It'll enter the atmosphere
in 40 seconds.
You're right.
There are some things...
very nice things worth saving;
beautiful things.
Beautiful things.
Like love?
Yes, love.
That's good. That's good.
That's a good example.
Love is worth saving.
I don't know love.
I was built to protect,
not love.
So there's no use for me
other than this.
You're wrong.
You're wrong. You're wrong.
I need you.
I need you,
very much.
Why?
Because...
because...
Tell her, Korben.
Tell me.
Please.
Why you need me?
Because...
Tell me.
- Tell me.
- Because I--
Because I love you.
I love you.
10...
9...
8...
7...
6, 5...
4, 3...
2...
1.
Scanner imaging has confirmed
the dark planet dead.
The planet seems to have stopped
at 62 miles from impact.
What's wrong?
What you screaming for?
Every five minutes
it's a bomb or something.
I'm leaving.
Mr. President.
Let me introduce Professor Mactilburgh
who runs the center.
It's an honor, Mr. President.
Where are my two heroes?
They were so tired from their ordeal,
we put them in the reactor.
I have 19 meetings after this.
Let me see
if they're revived.
Thank you.
We go live in one minute.
They're...
not ready.
They need...
five more minutes.
You have 20 seconds.
No, ma'am, I tried.
No, ma'am.
Who's that?
Some woman.
Claims to be Korben's mother.
Give it here.
Mrs. Dallas,
this is the President.
On behalf
of the Federation--
That doesn't
even sound like him.
The President's an idiot.
You don't sound like an idiot.
If you don't want to talk
to your mother...
just avoid me as usual.
I'll throw myself in traffic.
I'll Saran Wrap myself to the bed.